Preliminary Guide to the Devy Bendit papers, 1970-1985 MS2246
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Devy Bendit papers
1970-1985
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Bendit, Devy
MS2246
1 Linear Feet
This collection contains poetry, correspondence, art work, and publications related to the life and work of Devy Bendit a local poet and lawyer. The material is dated from 1970-85.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Collection aquired from Grace Cavalieri, 2007.
Historical or Biographical Note
Devy Bendit (d. 1984) was a lawyer and poet. Her work in the law included stints as a prosecutor in the Baltimore city state's attorney's office, corporate counsel for two local companies, designer of a pre-law program and faculty member at Antioch College in Columbia, MD, and executive director of the Mental Health Association of Metropolitan Baltimore. Known for championing of civil rights causes, she assisted in the legal defense of H. Rap Brown. She also assisted John Ehrichman in the writing of his memoirs. Bendit was also an accomplished poet. Her chapbook "Selling Parsley" was published in 1977 and her second book "Solid Gold" was published in 1982, both by The Bunny and the Crocodile Press. She attended the Breadloaf Writers' Conference and gave readings throughout Baltimore and Washington.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains poetry, correspondence, art work, and publications related to the life and work of Devy Bendit. It is a small collection, but does provide a good representation of Bendit's work as a poet. The materials have been refoldered into acid free folders, but titled with the original folder titles and kept in the original order. If no folder title was provided, staff generated a title that is hopefully reprentative of the materials in those folders. The material is dated from 1970-85. This collection was donated by Grace Cavalieri in 2007.
Collection Organization
This collection is not fully processed and series have not been defined.
Baltimore (Md.); Poetry; Cavalieri, Grace; Bendit, Devy
- Art work, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Art work, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Devy Bendit a personal essay by Grace Cavalieri, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Contract of Employment between Devy Bendit and John Ehrlichman, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Handwritten notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Journal, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Journal, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Journal of Grace Cavalieri, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- list of name and a bill fold, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous publications, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous publications, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- newspaper clippings, poems, postcards, 1970-1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Notebook, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Bendit obituary and poems, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Poems, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Poems, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Poems [1/2], undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Poems [2/2], undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Read My Name Please, Mount Royal School #66, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Slides of wearable art, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  General note
  coats decoarated in Bokango African Tradition of Slave Culture modeled by Grace Cavalieri.
- Transcript of Devy Bendit from University of Maryland, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- poems, correspondence and notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Poems, postcards and letters, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)